YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series II. Training and Personnel
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES II. TRAINING AND PERSONNEL
  - Reports
    - Secretary
      - Brinckerhoff, Margaret, 1919 (Box 366, Folder 8)
      - Bristle, Margaret McCague, 1920-21 (Box 366, Folder 9)
      - Broeksmit, Helen, 1920-21 (Box 366, Folder 10)
      - Brown, Linda Spence, 1919-20 (Box 366, Folder 11)
      - Brown, Marjorie, 1919-20 (Box 366, Folder 12)
      - Butcher, Theodora S., 1923-25 (Box 366, Folder 13)
      - Butler, Eliza R., 1919-23 (Box 366, Folder 14-15)
      - Carner, Lucy P., 1920-23 (Box 366, Folder 16)
      - Corbett, Mary J., 1919-21 (Box 366, Folder 17)
      - Cornish, Ruth H., 1919-21 (Box 366, Folder 18)
      - Craig, Ruth W. (Mrs. S.A.), 1919 (Box 366, Folder 19)
      - Crane, Helen Bond, 1918 (Box 366, Folder 20)
      - Curtis, Minerva, 1919-21 (Box 366, Folder 21)
      - Day, Inez P., 1919-20 (Box 366, Folder 22)
      - Dean, Elizabeth L., 1914-18 (Box 366, Folder 23)
      - Denison, Florence E., 1920-22 (Box 366, Folder 24)
      - Dodge, Grace H., 1910-14 (Box 366, Folder 25)
      - Dow, Caroline M., 1907-22 (Box 366, Folder 26-28)
      - Dunstone, Alice E., 1924-25 (Box 366, Folder 29)
      - Ebbesen, Aina, 1920 (Box 366, Folder 30)
      - Englesing, Edith, 1919 (Box 366, Folder 31)
      - Fenner, Jessamine C., 1925 (Box 366, Folder 32)
      - Ferris, Mary C., 1919-23 (Box 366, Folder 33)
      - Gladding, Effie Price (Mrs. Thomas S.), 1907-10 (Box 366, Folder 34)
      - Greene, Elsie, 1919 (Box 366, Folder 35)
      - Halsey, Katharine, 1919 (Box 366, Folder 36)
      - Hammerly, Sueanna, 1919-22 (Box 366, Folder 37)
      - Harbarger, Sada Annis, 1918-19 (Box 366, Folder 38)
      - Harrub, Deborah H., 1918-20 (Box 366, Folder 39)
      - Hawkes, Abigail T., 1919-23 (Box 366, Folder 40)
      - Hays, Emma, 1909-10 (Box 366, Folder 41)
      - Hirth, Emma, 1926-27 (Box 366, Folder 42)
      - Jenkins, E. Van Sant, 1921-24 (Box 366, Folder 43)
      - Keeney, Ruth, 1919-20 (Box 366, Folder 44)
      - Kindle, Ethel E., 1921 (Box 366, Folder 45)
      - Lapham, Joyce E., 1920 (Box 366, Folder 46)
      - Lautenbach, Marguerite, 1919-20 (Box 366, Folder 47)
      - Lyall, Agnes, 1920-21 (Box 366, Folder 48)
      - Lynch, Josephine F., 1920 (Box 366, Folder 49)
      - MacBride, Betty, 1919-23 (Box 367, Folder 1)
      - McCabe, Ethel C., 1919 (Box 367, Folder 2)
      - Melcher, Margery, 1919-20 (Box 367, Folder 3)
      - Morris, Alice V. (Mrs. Dave H.), 1919-20 (Box 367, Folder 4)
      - Nelson, Salome D., 1918-23 (Box 367, Folder 5)
      - Ogden, Helen, 1919 (Box 367, Folder 6)
      - Patchin, Mary A., 1919-20 (Box 367, Folder 7)
      - Reid, Edith M., 1919 (Box 367, Folder 8)
      - Reynolds, Annie M., 1914-18 (Box 367, Folder 9)
      - Rice, Anna V., 1923 (Box 367, Folder 10)
      - Riggs, May F., 1919 (Box 367, Folder 11)
      - Rockwell, Cleos, 1919 (Box 367, Folder 12)
      - Rowe, Marguerite E., 1923-24 (Box 367, Folder 13)
      - Rowlen, Belle, 1920 (Box 367, Folder 14)
      - Runnels, Grace N., 1919 (Box 367, Folder 15)
      - Sanger, Helen, 1914-19 (Box 367, Folder 16)
      - Santee, Mrs. I. M., 1920 (Box 367, Folder 17)
      - Scott, Anna M., 1919-24 (Box 367, Folder 18)
      - Scott, Mary Elizabeth, 1913-23 (Box 367, Folder 19)
      - Sheppard, Grace, 1920-25 (Box 367, Folder 20)
      - Stanton, Edith N., 1909-25 (Box 367, Folder 21-23)
      - Stevens, Ellen Yale, 1919-21 (Box 367, Folder 24)
      - Stevens, Nellie Starr, 1915-16 (Box 367, Folder 25)
      - [Stuart], Faith (Foxcroft), 1916-17 (Box 367, Folder 26)
      - Stuart, Marguerite, 1919 (Box 367, Folder 27)
      - Studebaker, Edna M., 1919 (Box 367, Folder 28)
      - Sturges, Sarah E.D., 1918-23 (Box 367, Folder 29)
      - Tag, Florence K., 1919 (Box 367, Folder 30)
      - Tanner, Elsie, 1918-19 (Box 367, Folder 31)
      - Tewksbury, Edith, 1919-21 (Box 367, Folder 32)
      - Troutt, Anna, 1919-20 (Box 367, Folder 33)
      - Upham, Bertha A., 1919-20 (Box 367, Folder 34)
      - Upham, Grace, 1919-20 (Box 367, Folder 35)
      - Van Horn, Olive, 1918-19 (Box 367, Folder 36)
      - Van Norden, Evelyn (Mrs. Theodore), 1920-21 (Box 367, Folder 37)
      - Walser, Olive Havelock, 1923-27 (Box 367, Folder 38)
      - Webb, Celeste, 1918-20 (Box 367, Folder 39)
      - Webster, Katharine, 1919 (Box 367, Folder 40)
      - Williams, Florence Marion, 1919 (Box 367, Folder 41)
      - Wilson, Elizabeth, 1907-18 (Box 367, Folder 42-44)
      - Wise, Helen W., 1918-20 (Box 367, Folder 45)
  - Scholarships
    - General, circa 1960-68, n.d. (Box 367, Folder 46)
    - Scholarship Fund Committee, 1950 (Box 367, Folder 47)
    - Scholarship/Scholarship and Loan Committee/Subcommittee, 1957-69 (Box 368, Folder 1-3)
    - Grace Dodge Merit Fellowship Award, 1960-98, n.d. (Box 368, Folder 4)
  - Studies
    - Report [title page missing] of a study on "the extent to which differences in culture patterns conditioned the adjustment processes of individuals shifting from experience in groups of relatively common cultural background to memberships in groups of diversified culture" by M.W. [Margaret Williamson?], n.d. (Box 368, Folder 5)
    - "Differences and Similarities of Perception of the YWCA by Leadership Persons," Harriet Naylor, 1963 (Box 368, Folder 6)
  - Training
    - General and History
      - Miscellaneous, 1905-2000, n.d. (Box 369, Folder 1-2)
      - "History of American Training of Young Women's Christian Association Secretaries, 1891-1918 Inclusive" by Elizabeth Wilson, Jan 1933 (Box 369, Folder 3)
      - Training for Group Experience, syllabus from course at Columbia University, 1927 (taken by YW staff, among others) (Box 369, Folder 4)
    - Training Program (schools, workshops, institutes, etc.)
      - Secretaries' Training Institute, Chicago: minutes and reports, 1906-08 (Box 369, Folder 5)
      - National Training System/Extension Training Division
        - General, 1912-20 (Box 369, Folder 6)
        - National Training School [1908-26]
          - General and History, 1915-85, n.d. (Box 369, Folder 7)
          - Memoranda: History and Policy of Administration of the National Training School, 23 Nov 1923 (Box 369, Folder 8)
          - Catalogues
            - 1908-13 (Box 369, Folder 9)
            - 1913-27 (Box 370, Folder 1-2)
          - Committee: minutes, 1921, 1925-28 (Box 370, Folder 3-4)
          - Candidates Council/Admissions Committee/Admissions Council, 1925-33 (Box 370, Folder 5)
          - Faculty Meetings, 1912-25 (Box 370, Folder 6-9)
          - Lecture notes, "The Association and the Woman Movement," Katherine Gerwick, 30 Apr-26 May 1926 (Box 371, Folder 1)
          - Scholarships and Loans/Scholarship Committee, 1923-33 (Box 371, Folder 2)
          - Reports, 1919-26 (Box 371, Folder 3)
          - Student papers, 1922-23 (Box 371, Folder 4-6)
        - Summer School/Sessions
          - General, 1929-40 (Box 371, Folder 7)
          - Asilomar and Berkeley, 1927-29 (Box 371, Folder 8)
          - Fletcher Farm, 1929-31 (Box 371, Folder 9)
          - Geneva, 1929-31 (Box 371, Folder 10)
          - Maqua, 1929 (Box 371, Folder 11)
          - New York: faculty meetings, 1922-37 (Box 371, Folder 12-13)
      - School for Professional Workers, 1951-60 (Box 371, Folder 14-15)
      - Orientation Institutes/Initial Training Institutes: general, 1968-73 (Box 371, Folder 16)
      - Venture Program, 1967-70, n.d. (Box 371, Folder 17)
      - National YWCA Pilot Workshops: report, 1980 (Box 371, Folder 18)
      - Learning Center [=Learning Center VII-early 1990s?] 1978
        - General
          - 1978-79 (Box 371, Folder 19)
          - 1980-89 (Box 372, Folder 1-5)
        - Library, bibliography, 1981, 1990-91 (Box 372, Folder 6)
      - Leadership Development Institutes [late 1990s-], 1994-2001, n.d. (Box 372, Folder 7-11)
    - Publications/Resource materials for training workshops
      - Handouts
        - General, 1962-92, n.d. (Box 373, Folder 1)
        - Evaluation forms (blanks), 1984-90 (Box 373, Folder 2)
        - YWCA history and mission, 1960-95, n.d. (Box 373, Folder 3)
        - Racism, Sexism, World, 1982-96, n.d. (Box 373, Folder 4)
      - Administration/"Executive Management"
        - Seminar on Supervision, 1956 (Box 373, Folder 5)
        - Democratic Process in Administration workshop, 1957 (Box 373, Folder 6)
        - "The Executive Decides" In-basket Procedure, circa 1960 (Box 373, Folder 7)
        - National YWCA Institute on Administration, 1971 (Box 373, Folder 8)
        - Management Workshop for Staff with Executive Potential: workbook, 1978-84 (Box 373, Folder 9)
        - Executive Management Workshop: participants manual, 1999 (Box 373, Folder 10)
        - Long Range Property and Facilities Planning, n.d. (Box 373, Folder 11)
      - Board training, n.d. (Box 373, Folder 12)
      - Convention: How Delegates Influence Policy Through the Convention, 1993 (Box 373, Folder 13)
      - Education for Global Responsibility workshops
        - General, 1995, n.d. (Box 373, Folder 14)
        - Resource manual, 1992 (Box 373, Folder 15)
      - Executive Director and President training
        - Executive Directors Institutes, 1959-60 (Box 373, Folder 16)
        - E.D. Orientation, 1983 (Box 373, Folder 17)
        - Executive Director and President Orientation, 1987, 1989 (Box 373, Folder 18-19)
      - Leadership Institutes, work book, 1946-47 (Box 374, Folder 1-2)
      - Marketing workshops, 1986-87 (Box 374, Folder 3)
      - Mission Empowerment Process: facilitators packet, circa 1998 (Box 374, Folder 4)
      - National Board
        - Orientation, 1982, 1988 (Box 374, Folder 5-6)
        - Retreat, 1987 (Box 374, Folder 7-8)
        - Workshop: Homophobia and Heterosexism, 1994-95 (Box 374, Folder 9)
      - Personnel Management, 1978, 1986, 1987 (Box 374, Folder 10-15)
      - Staff orientation and other training
        - Seminars for Experienced staff, 1954 (Box 374, Folder 16)
        - Induction Institutes, 1956 (Box 374, Folder 17)
        - Ohio Staff Round Table, 1962 (Box 374, Folder 18)
        - Initial Training A, 1965, 1967 (Box 374, Folder 19-20)
        - Initial Training C, 1965, 1966 (Box 374, Folder 21)
        - Initial Training Institutes, 1969 (Box 374, Folder 22)
        - New Executives' Briefing, 1988 (Box 374, Folder 23)
        - Racism and Heterosexism, 1996 (Box 375, Folder 1)
        - Training the Trainers, 1980 (Box 375, Folder 2)
        - Employee Orientation, 2000 (Box 375, Folder 3)
    - Publications/Resource Materials, General
      - Miscellaneous, 1945-80 (Box 375, Folder 4)
      - Administrative Management
        - General, 1907-85 (Box 375, Folder 5)
        - Administration in the YWCA series, 1944 (Box 375, Folder 6)
        - Basic Documents of a Community YWCA, 1965, 1967, 1990, 1992, 1995, 2001 (Box 375, Folder 7-11)
        - Business Administration Manual for Community YWCAs, 1962 (Box 375, Folder 12)
        - The Executive Director on the Job in a Membership Organization-the YWCA by Clark and Teall, 1947 (Box 376, Folder 1)
        - Executive Management for Women: A Trainer's Manual, 1982 (Box 376, Folder 2-3)
        - The Job at the Information Desk, n.d. (Box 376, Folder 4)
        - Maintenance and Housekeeping Manual for the YWCA (loose leaf series on administration no. 6), 1969 (Box 376, Folder 5)
        - Program Planning in the YWCA (loose leaf series on administration no. 8), 1975 (Box 376, Folder 6)
        - Recording and Reporting in the YWCA, n.d. (Box 376, Folder 7)
      - Board of Directors
        - General information pamphlet, 1974-98, n.d. (Box 376, Folder 8)
        - Role and responsibility, 1945-77, n.d. (Box 376, Folder 9-13)
        - Staff and Board, 1953-78 (Box 377, Folder 1-2)
      - Citizenship, 1914, 1952 (Box 377, Folder 3)
      - Committees
        - General, 1907, 1966 (Box 377, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous, 1913-63 (Box 377, Folder 5)
        - Committee Cues: The Basic Philosophy and Structure of Committee Work in the YWCA, circa 1939-47 (Box 377, Folder 6)
        - The Nominating Committee, 1944-98 (Box 377, Folder 7-8)
      - Constitutions, 1934-59, n.d. (Box 377, Folder 9-11)
      - Councils, 1931, n.d. (Box 378, Folder 1)
      - Group work
        - General, 1934-59 (Box 378, Folder 2)
        - How to Lead a Discussion by LeRoy E. Bowman, 1946-51 (Box 378, Folder 3)
        - How to Prepare a Speech by Ivan Gerould Grimshaw, TWP, 1952 (Box 378, Folder 4)
        - Social Group Work: Principles and Practices by Harleigh Trecker, TWP, 1948 (Box 378, Folder 5)
      - Leadership Development, 1939-42 (Box 378, Folder 6)
      - Orientation
        - National Board kits
          - 1978 (Box 378, Folder 7)
          - 1979, 1982, 1985 (Box 379, Folder 1-3)
        - 'Ready Reference' for new presidents and executive directors, 1988, circa 1992, Jun 1997 (Box 379, Folder 4-6)
        - Staff
          - 1950-87 (Box 379, Folder 7-13)
          - circa 1988-2000 (Box 380, Folder 1-3)
      - Parliamentary procedure, 1919-68 (Box 380, Folder 4)
      - Performance Evaluation, 1940-98 (Box 380, Folder 5)
      - Personnel administration
        - 1933-66 (Box 380, Folder 6-13)
        - 1970-99 (Box 381, Folder 1-6)
      - Salary and Benefit surveys
        - 1931-59 (Box 381, Folder 7-10)
        - 1960-98 (Box 382, Folder 1-3)
      - Search packet, circa 1985 (Box 382, Folder 4)
      - Standards of Work, circa 1921, 1935-36 (Box 382, Folder 5)
      - Supervision, 1940-80 (Box 382, Folder 6)
      - Supervision Principles and Methods by Margaret Williamson, TWP, 1950 (Box 382, Folder 7)
      - Union relations, 1945-47, n.d. (Box 382, Folder 8)
  - Volunteers
    - General and History
      - 1916-83, n.d. (Box 382, Folder 9)
      - Paper: "The Invisible Work Force: Recruiting and Retaining Volunteers in the 1990s" by Sandra A. Vincent, Loyola University, Feb 1992 (Box 382, Folder 10)
    - Committees/Department
      - Volunteer Workers Bureau, [see also Record Group 1. Series V. Biographical files-Morris, Alice V.]
        - Minutes, 1919-21 (Box 383, Folder 1-2)
        - Reports, 1919-21 (Box 383, Folder 3-4)
      - Commission on Training Volunteer Workers: report to Convention, 1913 (Box 383, Folder 5)
      - Advisory Committee on Volunteer Training, 1923-25 (Box 383, Folder 6)
      - Committee Interested in Volunteer Training, 1933-34 (Box 383, Folder 7)
      - Volunteer Training/Leadership Committee, 1926-40 (Box 383, Folder 8-11)
      - Leadership Services Department Committee on Volunteers, Oct 1943-45 (Box 383, Folder 12)
      - Ad-hoc Committee on Use and Training of National Board Volunteers, 1965 (Box 383, Folder 13)
      - National Volunteer Leadership Committee, 1965-69 (Box 383, Folder 14)
    - Career Volunteer Development Project
      - General, 1979-89 (Box 383, Folder 15-16)
      - Volunteer Study, 1982 (Box 383, Folder 17)
      - Notebook, circa 1983 (Box 383, Folder 18)
      - Training of Trainers notebook, 18-21 Feb 1983 (Box 383, Folder 19-20)
    - Training
      - General, 1913-56, n.d. (Box 384, Folder 1)
      - "Materials for Volunteer Leadership Training," 1956 (Box 384, Folder 2)
      - "New Materials for use in Volunteer Training in YWCAs," 1958 (Box 384, Folder 3)
      - "Administrative Volunteers Management Training Manual," 1975 (Box 384, Folder 4)
      - Handbooks
        - Pages for a Volunteer's Note Book, 1923-25 (Box 384, Folder 5)
        - General, 1932, 1934 (Box 384, Folder 6)
        - Primer for Volunteers, 1951-62 (Box 384, Folder 7)
        - A Handbook for New Administrative Volunteers, 1981 (Box 384, Folder 8)
      - Program volunteers, 1937, n.d. (Box 384, Folder 9)
      - Training manuals
        - Recruitment and supervision, 1936-51, n.d. (Box 384, Folder 10)
        - Teens, adolescents, 1949, n.d. (Box 384, Folder 11)
      - Manuals/packets for training workshops
        - Leadership Development Day packet, 1956 (Box 385, Folder 1)
        - Institute on Volunteer Training, 1957 (Box 385, Folder 2)
        - Volunteer training notebook, circa 1964 (Box 385, Folder 3)
    - Thank you notes to Caroline Dow removed from National Training School scrapbook listed below (Box 385, Folder 4)
  - OVERSIZE
    - National Training School: scrapbook compiled by Caroline Dow, Dean of the School, 1908-12 (Box 385)
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    - National Association of Employed Officers/National Association of Professional Workers (Box 385)
      - General and History, 1924-89, n.d. (Box 386, Folder 1)
      - Committees/Commissions
        - Advisory Committee on Personal Counseling, Counseling Service (Box 386)
          - General correspondence and reports, 1932-34 (Box 386, Folder 2)
          - Correspondence with participants, 1933-41 (Box 386, Folder 3-7)
          - Evaluations of Service, 1933-34, 1936 (Box 386, Folder 8)
        - Executive Committee Annual Meeting, 1950-52 (Box 386, Folder 9)
        - To Study the Union Proposal, 1936-37 (Box 386, Folder 10)
      - Conferences/Conventions
        - Proceedings and reports, 1920-40 (Box 386, Folder 11-13)
        - Addresses, 1936, 1940 (Box 386, Folder 14)
      - Constitution and Bylaws, 1946 (Box 387, Folder 1)
      - Dissolution proceedings, 1951-53 (Box 387, Folder 2)
      - Publications
        - The Bulletin, 1932-52 (Box 387, Folder 3)
        - Directories of Employed Officers/Executive Directors, 1929, 1948 (Box 387, Folder 4)
        - The Future of Administration: The Transition from "For" to "With," 1943 (Box 387, Folder 5)
        - Reports, 1932, 1943 (Box 387, Folder 6)
    - National Association of YWCA Executives (NAYE) est 1985, 1985-99 (Box 387, Folder 7)